newegg.com 2019-10-28

# Privacy Policy – Newegg Knowledge Base

### Privacy Policy

This privacy policy tells you about the information we collect from you when you use any website or mobile application owned or operated by Newegg, its subsidiaries and affiliates, including Newegg websites around the world (collectively, the “Site”), including information about who we are, what information we collect, why we use your information, who we share your information with and why, how we protect your information, and how you can change or review your information. By using our services, and the Site, you understand and consent to Newegg collecting, storing, processing, and sharing your information as described in this privacy policy. If you do not agree with our policies and practices, do not use the Site.

### Who are we?

We, along with our affiliates and subsidiaries, are Newegg. Our address is 18045 Rowland St., City Of Industry, CA 91748. You can contact us by mail at the above address, by email at [wecare@service.newegg.com](mailto:wecare@service.newegg.com) or by our other contact methods listed here: <https://help.newegg.com/contactus>.

### What personal information do we collect?

**Information collected voluntarily**

We collect information that you voluntarily provide to us, such as when you register for an account or place an order with Newegg. We may combine this information with other information that we have collected about you. We may use cookies, log files, web beacons, JavaScript, and other similar technology (“Cookies and Similar Technology”) to collect and store the information we collect.

**Account Registration**

To register for a Newegg account, you must provide us with your personal information, including your name, email address, and password.

**Purchase Order Information**

You are not required to have an account to place an order with us. You may place an order either through your account or through guest checkout, which provides an opportunity to create an account during checkout.

In order to place an order with Newegg, you must provide us with your name, shipping address, billing address, telephone number, and payment information, such as your credit card number, billing address, credit card expiration date, and credit card security code.

**Information Stored on a Device**

With your consent, we may access metadata and other information associated with other files stored on your computer, tablet, mobile phone, or any other device (referred to collectively as a “Device”).

**Location Information**

With your consent, which you provide when you install our mobile application, when you access and use our mobile application, we may collect information about the general location of a Device.

**Information collected automatically**

When you access and use the Site on a Device, we may automatically collect information about a Device, such as the IP address, and device identifier (“Device Information”). We may associate the information we collect from a Device with your account. In addition, we may associate a Device with your account. We may combine this information with other information that we have collected about you. We may use cookies, log files, web beacons, JavaScript, and other similar technology (“Cookies and Similar Technology”) to collect and store the information we collect.

### Why do we use your personal information?

We may use your personal information for a variety of business purposes, including:

  * Where necessary to provide you with access to our services, and the Site;
  * Where necessary to provide you with interactive features on the Site;
  * Where necessary to provide our services to you or for the performance of a contract;
  * Where necessary to process and fulfill your orders and returns and exchanges;
  * Where necessary to contact you if we have trouble processing your order;
  * Where necessary to provide you with customer support and to respond to your requests, comments, questions, or concerns;
  * Where necessary to send you information about your order, such as order updates;
  * Where necessary to process and manage your subscriptions;
  * Where necessary to fulfill your benefits that are associated with your use of our services, such as to award points through our EggPoint loyalty program;
  * Where necessary to administer sweepstakes and contests that you have entered into;
  * Where necessary to customize your settings;
  * Where necessary to send you important notices, such as system notices and alerts, and changes to our terms and conditions, and policies;
  * Where necessary to comply with applicable laws and legal obligations;
  * Where necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on Newegg;
  * Where necessary for our legitimate interest in preventing and detecting fraud, and maintaining security;
  * Where necessary for our legitimate interests in enforcing our terms and conditions, and policies;
  * Where necessary for our legitimate interests in analyzing and improving the effectiveness of the Site, and our products and services;
  * Where you consent to Newegg sending you our newsletters, special promotions, and offers;
  * Where you consent to Newegg sending you text alerts and/or email notifications;
  * Where you consent to Newegg sending you push notifications on a Device; and
  * Where you consent to Newegg sending you marketing communications, advertisements and other information relating to our products and services.

### Cookies and Similar Technology

We use Cookies and Similar Technologies in order to provide our services, to analyse and improve our services, to prevent and detect fraud, to customize your account settings, and to personalize your experience of the Site through the use of targeted advertisements and offers.

**Cookies**

A cookie is a small text file that is generated by a site that is stored on a Device. When you access the Site, a number of cookies are used by Newegg and third parties. We may link data stored in cookies to the personal information you submitted while on the Site.

**Log file**

We may use Device Information to analyze trends, administer the Site, track user movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. We may store the information in log files or other types of files, which may be combined with other information that we have collected about you.

**Web Beacon**

The Site and our emails and advertisements may contain web beacons. A web beacon is a small graphic image, such as a pixel or GIF, which is placed on a web page, email, or advertisement and is used to provide information on when and how you access and use the Site, and services. We may allow third-party companies to collect non-personal information when you visit the Site. These companies typically use a cookie or web beacon to collect this information in order to provide advertisements likely to be of interest to you.

**Functional**

Some of the Cookies and Similar Technology that we use are strictly necessary for the Site to function and cannot be turned off. As a result, if you choose to reject the cookies, you cannot browse our store or place an order with Newegg. We use Cookies and Similar Technology for various necessary and legitimate business purposes, including to enable you to register, access and update your account; to allow you to make a purchase; in order for Newegg to analyze and improve the performance of our services, and the Site; to maintain security on the Site, and to prevent and detect fraud; to customize your account; and to display certain web page content based upon your browser type and other information provided by our Cookies and Similar Technology.

**Personalized Experience and Offers**

Subject to your cookie settings, Newegg and various third parties may use Cookies and Similar Technology to personalize your experience on the Site, such as through the use of targeted advertisements and special offers. We have no access to or control over third-party technologies. In addition, please note that this privacy policy covers Newegg’s use of Cookies and Similar Technology only and does not cover third-party use of their own proprietary technologies.

**Third-Party Services Cookies**

Subject to your cookie settings, Newegg and third-party service providers that you may subscribe to may require Cookies and Similar Technologies to allow you to use those third-party services in connection with your use of our services, and the Site. We have no access to or control over third-party technologies. In addition, please note that this privacy policy covers the use of Cookies and Similar Technologies by Newegg only and does not cover the use of technologies by any third-party service providers.

**Do Not Track Signals or Similar Mechanisms**

Some web browsers have a “Do Not Track” feature that, when turned on, signals to websites the user visits that the user does not want to be tracked. At this time, the Site does not respond to “Do Not Track” signals or similar mechanisms.

We may share or disclose your personal information at your direction or request, or upon your consent, such as when you authorize a third-party application to access your account or when you direct us to share your feedback with a marketplace seller or other business.

We may also share your personal information between:

**Marketplace Sellers**

Third-Party sellers offer products for sale through Newegg’s Marketplace platform. We refer to these third parties as Marketplace Sellers. In order to best facilitate and complete Marketplace Seller Transactions, we may share some of your personal information with these third parties.

**Service Providers**

In order to process your credit card information to complete your purchase, we must share your personal and financial information with the merchant bank for authorization and approval. This process is protected by an enhanced security system. See the Security section below for more details on security measures and procedures.

In addition, we may employ third-party companies to perform functions on our behalf. These functions may include order fulfillment, package delivery, marketing assistance, postal and e-mail delivery, customer service, data analysis, and credit processing. The third parties we contract for these purposes have limited access to your personal information and may not use it for other purposes.

**Affiliated Institutions**

We may share your personal information we collect with all Newegg subsidiaries and affiliates.

As our business continues to evolve, we may acquire or sell business units or subsidiaries. Customer information is one of the business assets that would be transferred in these types of transactions. In such a situation, your personal information would only be used in a manner consistent with our pre-existing Privacy Notice and terms and conditions.

**As Required by Law**

We reserve the right to disclose your personal information as required by law, and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on Newegg.

**Third-Party Companies for Marketing**

Subject to your marketing preferences and settings, we may share your personal information with third-party companies that may, among other things, use your personal information to provide you with targeted advertisements and special offers. To change your settings, go to the account settings section of this privacy policy. The companies will only be allowed to use your personal information in accordance with your marketing preferences and will be required to keep your personal information secure.

**Collection and Use of Non-Personal Information**

We may collect, use, store, transfer, share, and disclose non-personal information for any purpose.

**Collection and Use of Public Information**

We may collect, use, store, transfer, share, and disclose your information that is publicly available, such as information you submit on social media platforms, or blogs for any purpose.

**Links**

The Site may contain links to other third-party websites or applications. Please be aware that these websites and applications may collect information about you. These websites and applications may have their own privacy notices or policies. We encourage you to be aware when you leave the Site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website and application that you use. This privacy policy applies only to information collected by the Site. To the extent any linked websites or applications you visit are not owned or operated by Newegg, please be aware that we are not responsible for the websites or applications’ content, any use of the websites or applications, or the privacy and security practices and policies of those websites or applications.

**Testimonial/Feedback about our Services**

The testimonial/feedback sections of the Site are for the purpose of sharing experiences and providing feedback about the Site. The testimonial/feedback sections are moderated to ensure accurate testimonial/feedback. Published testimonial/feedback are genuine and are not edited or altered by Newegg. Newegg reserves the right to post or remove any testimonial/feedback at its discretion.

By posting your testimonial/feedback, you give us permission to reprint or use the testimonial/feedback in connection with our business. You also are agreeing to the following: (1) The reprint or use of the testimonial/feedback will be at our discretion and without compensation; (2) We may use the testimonial/feedback with or without any pseudo (pen) name credit; (3) Our right to use the testimonial/feedback is perpetual and may be assigned by us; (4) We may use the testimonial/feedback locally, nationally or globally and such use may be made in any media, information or communication platform (including Internet advertising) currently in use or later developed; and (5) You and not someone else composed and posted the testimonial/feedback.

Please note that any information you include in a testimonial/feedback may be read, collected, and used by anyone.

**Testimonial/Reviews about Products**

The testimonial/reviews sections of the Site are for the purpose of sharing experiences and product reviews. The testimonial/reviews sections are moderated to ensure accurate testimonial/reviews. Published testimonial/reviews are genuine and are not edited or altered by Newegg. Newegg reserves the right to post or remove any testimonial/reviews at its discretion.

By posting your testimonial/reviews, you give us permission to reprint or use the testimonial/reviews in connection with our business. You also are agreeing to the following: (1) The reprint or use of the testimonial/reviews will be at our discretion and without compensation; (2) We may use the testimonial/reviews with or without any pseudo (pen) name credit; (3) Our right to use the testimonial/reviews is perpetual and may be assigned by us; (4) We may use the testimonial/reviews locally, nationally or globally and such use may be made in any media, information or communication platform (including Internet advertising) currently in use or later developed; and (5) You and not someone else composed and posted the testimonial/reviews.

Please note that any information you include in a testimonial/reviews may be read, collected, and used by anyone.

**Newegg Insider, GameCrate, and Unlocked (Blogs)**

By posting your comment(s) on our blogs, including, but not limited to, Newegg Insider, GameCrate, or Unlocked (“Blog” or “Blogs”), you give us permission to reprint or use the comments in connection with our business. You also are agreeing to the following: (1) The reprint or use of the comment will be at our discretion and without compensation; (2) We may use the comment with or without any pseudo (pen) name credit; (3) Our right to use the comment is perpetual and may be assigned by us; (4) We may use the Blog locally, nationally, or globally and such use may be made in any media, information or communication platform (including Internet advertising) currently in use or later developed; and (5) You and not someone else composed and posted the comment on our Blog.

Please note that any information you include in a comment on our Blog may be read, collected, and used by anyone.

**Posting Testimonial, and Blogs with Photos**

We may allow you to post testimonial, and Blogs that include photos. We will not access your photos or camera until we obtain your consent and we will only use the photos that you have selected. You can manage your photos and camera settings at any time by changing the settings on your mobile device.

**Social Media Platforms**

We maintain presences on social media platforms including, but not limited to, Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, and YouTube. Any information you post on a social media platform is done at your own risk and without any expectation of privacy. Please be aware that Newegg is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites.

### How do we protect your information?

**Security**

Newegg takes precautions to protect its customers’ information. When you submit sensitive information via the Site, your information is protected both online and offline.

When our registration/order form asks you to enter sensitive information (such as your credit card number), that information is encrypted and is protected using SSL encryption software. To learn more about SSL, follow this link: [www.verisign.com](http://www.verisign.com/).

Access to all of our users’ information is restricted. Newegg operates in a secured and locked facility that requires all employees to check in and wear valid ID badges. Security cameras are positioned throughout the building in conjunction with multiple alarm systems. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job are granted access to personal information.

If you have any questions or concerns about Newegg’s security practices, you can send us an email at [privacy@newegg.com](mailto:privacy@newegg.com).

**Retention Period**

We will retain your personal information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this policy, unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law.

**Safeguarding Information**

To ensure that your user name and password remain confidential, DO NOT share this information with anyone.

**Children**

Newegg does not sell products intended for purchase by children. Youth-oriented products are sold for purchase by adults only. If you are under the legal age of majority in your jurisdiction, you may only use the Site in the presence of a consenting parent or guardian. We will not knowingly or intentionally collect personal information from children under the age of 13. Newegg is committed to protecting the welfare and privacy of children.

**California Residents**

If you are a California resident and have an established business relationship with us, you may submit a request to us to obtain certain information regarding our disclosure of your personal information within the immediately preceding calendar year to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To submit a request, please send an email to [privacy@newegg.com](mailto:privacy@newegg.com).

**Nevada Residents**

By law, if you are a resident of Nevada, you have the right to opt-out of the sale of certain types of personal information about you. To submit a request, please send an email to [privacy@newegg.com](mailto:privacy@newegg.com).

### How can you change or review your information?

You may change or review your account information and settings for the following:

**Account Information**

When you register for a Newegg account, you enter your email address. This email address is your Newegg ID and the email address that you use to log in to the Site. To change your email address and Newegg ID on Newegg, from our desktop website, please go to [Account Settings](https://secure.newegg.com/NewMyAccount/AccountSettings.aspx). You cannot change your email address and Newegg ID from the Newegg mobile application or mobile website. Please note that you must have your email address/Newegg ID and password in order to access your account.

**Special Offers**

At the time of your order, you may choose to receive special offers and news by clicking the appropriate field.

If you currently receive special offers and news and wish to stop receiving special offers and news, Newegg provides several ways to do so. You may send e-mails to [wecare@service.newegg.com](mailto:wecare@service.newegg.com) with a request to be removed. Finally, you may use the link provided in all Newegg communications to automatically unsubscribe. Please note that you might still receive intermittent updates on products, services, specials or news.

**Push Notifications**

If you currently receive push notifications and wish to stop receiving push notifications, you can deactivate these notifications at any time by changing the settings on your mobile device.

**Uninstall Mobile Application**

You can stop all further collection of information by our mobile application by uninstalling our mobile application. You may use the standard uninstall process to remove our mobile application from your mobile device.

### Updates to this privacy policy

We regularly review and, if appropriate, update this privacy policy from time to time, and as our services and use of personal data evolves. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our homepage.

We will update the date of this document each time it is changed.

**Last Update**

The Privacy Policy contained herein became officially effective June 19, 2018.
